esubulletin.com 2016-12-30

# Client Site Privacy Policy | SNO Sites

School Newspapers Online Privacy Policy

We’ve compiled this privacy policy as an effort to be transparent about sites on the SNO FLEX platform collect, store, use, protect, and otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information (PII). PII, as defined by US privacy law, can be used to identify, contact, or locate an individual. Please read this information carefully.

**What personal information is collected from the people that visit a SNO website?**

In order to help us serve you more efficiently, we may ask for your name, email address, mailing address, phone number or other details.

**When is this information collected?**

We collect information from you when you fill out a contact form, sign up for our newsletter, or browse our website.

**How is this information used?**

This information may be used to help us serve you better and to provide you with the services you’ve requested.

**How is this information protected?**

SNO websites are regularly scanned for security holes, malware, and other vulnerabilities. Your personal information is contained within secured networks and is only viewable by a limited number of persons who have special access to these networks. These people are required to keep the information confidential.

**What information do we disclose to third parties?**

We _do not_ sell, trade, or otherwise share your personally identifiable information. We do not allow third party behavioral tracking. Additionally, we do not include or offer third party products or services on our website.

**How does our site handle “do not track” signals?**

We honor “do not track” signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Demographics and Interests Reporting**

We, along with third-party vendors such as Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions, and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

You can choose how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. You can also opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page, or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out browser add-on.

**Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States, and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices, should a data breach occur, we will notify the users via email within 7 business days. We also agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

**CalOPPA (California Online Privacy Protection Act)**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. – See more at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

**According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:**

  * Users can visit our site anonymously.
  * Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.
  * Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.
  * Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes on our Privacy Policy page.
  * Users are able to change their personal information by emailing or calling us.

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online. We do not specifically market to children under 13.

**CAN-SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

**We collect your email address in order to:**

  *   ****Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

**To be accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:**

  *   ****NOT use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses
  *   ****Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way
  *   ****Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters
  *   ****Monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  *   ****Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly
  *   ****Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can follow the instructions at the bottom of each email. We will promptly remove you from all correspondence.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact us via email, telephone, or postal mail.

School Newspapers Online

PO Box 2277

Burnsville, MN 55337

(888) 649-7784

Last edited: 2015-01-06 ** **  
****
